Pinelli mss. 1947-1985 LMC 2189
Lilly Library
Pinelli mss.
1968-1983
Lilly Library
Pinelli, Tullio.
LMC 2189
17 Items
Consists of film scripts written by Italian filmmaker Federico Fellini, 1920-, and scriptwriter Tullio Pinelli.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
The Pinelli mss., 1968-1983 contains the film scripts of Italian filmmaker Federico Fellini (1920-1993) and his scriptwriter Tullio Pinelli (1908-2009). Born in Piedmont, Italy, Pinelli initially sought work as a civil lawyer, but eventually became more invested in writing for the theater. He is known for his collaborations with Italian film director Federico Fellini. Their collaborative work of note includes the films I Vitelloni (1953), La Strada (1954), La Dolce Vita (1960), and 8 ½ (1963). Pinelli also worked on The Opium Den (1947) and Symphony of Love (1954).
Arrangement
Scripts are listed by title.
Scope and Content Note
The Pinelli mss., 1947-1985, consist of film scripts written by Italian filmmaker Federico Fellini, 1920-, and scriptwriter Tullio Pinelli.
Acquisition Information
Acquired: 1988
Motion picture film; Motion picture producers and directors --Italy.
- Collection (Box 1)
  - Senza pietà., 1947 (Box 1)
  - Luci del varietà., 1950 (Box 1)
  - Lo sciecco bianco., 1950 (Box 1)
  - I vitelloni., 1952 (Box 2)
  - La strada., 1953 (Box 2)
  - Il bidone., 1955 (Box 3)
  - La strada., 1954; (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Le notti di Cabiria., 1957 (Box 3)
  - La dolce vita., 1959; (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - Giulietta degli spiriti., 1965 (Box 4)
  - Ginger and Fred., 1985 (Box 4)
  - Le notti di Cabiria., 1957 (Box 4)
  - La famiglia., undated (Box 5)
  - Happy Country., undated (Box 5)
  - Il brigante di Tacca del Lupo., undated (Box 5)
  - Persiana chiuse., undated (Box 5)
  - Il diavolo in convento., undated (Box 5)